Welcome back. Now, after you have analyzed the mapping sheet, you will
decide on the technical requirements. Now, what do I mean by that?
Take a look at, this worksheet here.
It has information about the partitioning strategy.
You will mention that. And you already know that the partitioning is going to be
based on,
the day as such. You will just mention that here, in fact. Okay?
And then you will decide
things such as the storage format.
You want to store data in the curated
and aggregated, right? So what format?
Source, of course, is in Parquet. Do you want to continue Parquet or something
else? So you go with Parquet. Why? Parquet is one of the best
formats for big data engineering.
And then you then think about, okay, how do we implement the
code in what service of AWS? You decide to go with
AWS Glue, okay? Processing engine mentioned here, in fact.
And how often will this job run? It's going to run-- Data comes every month, right?
So obviously data-- the job will run every month, right?
So you're, you're trying to
design the pipeline now, okay?
You're, you're thinking the big picture, okay?
Storage format, where do I process it?
Uh, of course, in Spark. If it's in Spark, in which service
of AWS? I'll choose Glue. And then how often will I run the job?
It's a monthly batch job, so monthly data comes in, so I'll run the job
monthly when data comes in. And then very, very important is the processing part
called as idempotency. This is very important thing, in data engineering.
So what it means is that,
let's say data has come in today and, you have run the
job and loaded data in your curated layer
and also aggregated, and if you run this job again, then the
data should again get loaded in curated
and aggregated without affecting the existing data over
there, okay? In the sense, first time you load data here, okay?
There are a hundred records. Second time, again you run it for the same data,
right? Let me just repeat this. You have file one, hundred
records. You load data in, let's say,
target, a hundred records. For whatever reason,
you had to run the job again. Something failed, you want to rerun it, whatever it
is.
The same file is there, not the new file.
Same file, hundred, with a hundred records.
When you run the job with the sa-- again, the same file, it should go
and overwrite this data, a hundred records here.
It should not add hundred more. It should not become two
hundred. You're getting it, right?
Initially, a hundred was there the first run.
When you ran it again, you shouldn't be adding hundred more.
That is idempotency. No matter how many times you run it, for the same source data,
target should not change. For the same source data, when you run again and again,
target should not change. That is idempotency. Okay?
And then you decide, of course, you write down the query tool.
Of course, the
a-analyst will use Athena for the analysis.
And
analysts have also told you that, you know, once the analysis is all done, when you
have given them the aggregated data, when, when they have fired the queries,
ultimately, they'll build the reports
on a tool called as AWS QuickSight.
It's a reporting tool, reporting service, AWS QuickSight. Okay?
Just remember this. And then you also have
the catalog mentioned here. The Glue cat-- Glue Data Catalog is a catalog.
And of course, you'll be monitoring the data quality as well.
So if you have records that
mee-meet these data quality rejection scenario, you will
simply go ahead and reject them and capture the rejection rates.
That is what you mention here in the log as I display in the log.
And for, for performance, you will, obviously, you will
store data in the partition format by day, and you will
ask
the analyst team to filter the data based on these
partition columns so that, as we discussed in the
past, when they use the right filters, such as month
equal to this and day equal to this, that day's data
alone will be scanned from S3.
Right? I told you this in the past as well, that if you go to S3 and let's say
you-- here you have tw-twenty twenty-four and month zero one,
when you fire a query on this HV FHW table, add these two
filters, only this file will get scanned,
okay? That-- Which is, four fifty MB.
Other data in the raw folder will not get scanned.
So the-- You will be able to save the cost
of Athena by not scanning everything,
and also it'll run a lot faster, in fact. That is for performance tuning as well.
And then
you'll also mention about the data retention. Now, data is coming into your raw.
You want to be processing it, storing it into your curated
and aggregated, but how, how many days? How many years?
Now, based on your company's compliance policies, legal compliance
policies, you know, you will want to store them for seven years.
Just an example. Depends on every company.
But I'm just telling you that every company has their own policies for it.
And you mention here how you're going to implement that.
I mentioned S3 Lifecycle rule here.
You will see that shortly when we do the hands-on. So that's it.
You're now ready for development now.
So go to step four, and you start your development. Okay?
So I'll be sharing you the notebook now.
What I mean by notebook is, this thing right here, in fact.
We'll do this hands-on in the next few videos. And, the code is right here.
I'll be sharing the code with you, in fact. Okay?
And this code actually does the raw to curated
transformations. So the next few videos are completely hands-on.
So make sure you just follow them to the T and do your hands-on. Okay?
And if you really want to know how I build the code, then go to this
course, a short course called as RAID, Big Da-- Building Data Engineering Code
with Agentic AI. It's a short course.
I have explained to you how
this notebook code is built using Agentic AI feature of Amazon Q, in fact. Okay?
It's, it's a pretty interesting one.
And, after you go through that, I thinkYou
won't really have any fear of coding at all.
And one last thing is that the transformation logic mentioned here, these are all,
you know, SQL, things, okay? Which is discussed
in the SQL Skill Booster course, but the transformation logic can be implemented in
SQL or PySpark. So
make sure that you have gone through the SQL Skill Booster and Python and
PySpark Skill Booster, before you actually
go to the next video. Because there's no point in just doing what I'm telling you.
Understand that. And, and the reason why I have split
the entire
program into multiple courses is because I want to cater to
multiple personas here. I have people from different
backgrounds, from no experience to even twenty, twenty-five experience in my
community. So I strongly hope you appreciate what I'm doing
here. And lastly, once we are done with the entire,
development, right, I'm going to be sharing with you a
document. So what happens is
when we are done with the development entirely, okay?
Now, again, development and testing and production, these are-- this is a
development life cycle. Now, as the part
of you handing over the project to your support
team, you will get a document, you know, like this, where you
list down
what project you have implemented and, what is the source, what is
the target, right? What is the solution?
All of that is mentioned here. So we'll just walk you through this so that
you're able to connect all the dots together later.
And, and before you really go to the next video and do your hands-on, in fact,
okay, I-I wanna make sure
you note down
what you have learned so far in the comment below this video, okay?
Because I want really to see what you have learned so far.
It'll help me to help you better. It, it'll help me understand if
you are understanding, what you're understanding, so that I can improve and I can
help you better, in fact. Okay, so make sure you actually write down in your
comments below what you have learned so far, what story you have learned so far in
your own words. And read what others have also written.
See what-- how they actually interpret what I've told
already-- told you, in fact. Everybody has their own interpretation, right?
You get the point. All right, fasten your seat belts and, get going
with, the hands-on. Make sure you do them to the
T.